Arturo Vargas Cuevas

Electronics Engineer

Mexico City, Mexico

\$\\$\\$+52 55 3399 9589

@ a.vargas_c@outlook.com

Profiles

in Arturo Vargas Cuevas

AVargas-C

Languages

Spanish Native

English Advanced (C1)

German Basic (A2)

Hard Skills

Embedded Programming Advanced

C, C++, SystemC, Arduino, Assembler, VHDL

Design Tools
Intermediate

Proteus, PS-CAD, TINA-TI, Solidworks, MATLAB, Simulink

Prototyping Skills Advanced

Oscilloscopes, Multimeters, Spectrum Analyzers, Soldering Web Development
Intermediate

SQL, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Operating Systems & Command Line Tools Advanced

Bash, Linux, macOS, Windows, Git

Analog & Digital Communication Systems Intermediate

UART, I2C, SPI, AM/FM, QAM, QPSK

Certifications

Peer Mentoring Diploma Tecnológico de Monterrey

2023 Certificate

Entrepreneurship bootcamp for engineering

Tecnológico de Monterrey

Entrepreneurship Diploma

TrepCamp 2021

Leadership Diploma

Tecnológico de Monterrey **2020**

Awards

2nd place in the Graduation Projects of my Campus

School of Engineering and Science of Tecnológico de Monterrey CCM

June 2024

<u>LinkedIn</u>

CENEVAL National Award CENEVAL

May 2024

Certificate

Scholarship for studies in Germany

Baden-Württemberg-STIPENDIUM Oct. 2023 - Jan. 2024

Scholarship for TrepCamp Program

Becas Santander Mar. 2021 Technology enthusiast with a curious, passionate, and innovative mindset, always striving to stay at the forefront of the field. Love getting out of my comfort zone for new experiences. Fast learner, good at self-management and self-study. Inspiring leader, stand out for problem solving. Loves to help others.

Education

M.Sc. in Communications and Information Technology

Sept. 2023 - Present (paused)

Universität Ulm (Germany)

Completed 2 semesters. Currently on a leave of absence. Part of the **Advanced Master Placement Program** between Tecnológico de Monterrey and Ulm University.

B.Sc. in Electronics Engineering

Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2024

Tecnológico de Monterrey (Mexico City Campus)

During my career I gained international experience, CENEVAL national award, second best graduation project in engineering, I founded a drone racing team, I was a peer mentor and currently I am advisor on time management and international programs in the welfare and counseling department of my campus.

Experience

UP Electric (Consultant for Grupo Televisa)

Independent Electronics Engineer & Full Stack Developer

Aug. 2024 - present Hybrid, Mexico City

- Selected by UP Electric to develop PowerTIC product for Grupo Televisa as part of a consulting agreement. Implemented IoT and WebApp solutions tailored to energy management and data analysis.
- Developed robust real-time power monitoring solutions using advanced technologies such as React, PostgreSQL, and embedded systems.

MPower (Consultant for Grupo Elektra)

Logistics and Technical Support Staff

Helped develop and deliver the CoachingRED program.

May 2022 - Sep. 2024 Remote, Mexico

May 2024 - June 2024

Sep. 2022 - Present

Projects

Capstone Project (SmartNET)

In collaboration with UP-Electric

GitHub

We designed a hardware and software IoT solution for the requirements of the Engineering Department of the Estadio Azteca.

Won the 2nd place in the engineering graduation projects of my campus. (Jun. 2024)

Entrepreneurship

Chinampac

CONECTA (TEC de Monterrey Newsletter)

Member of an entrepreneurship focused on attacking hunger in Mexico and creating a more sustainable future. Developer of the electrical technologies.

- We won the National Sprite Challenge by Fundación Azteca of Grupo Salinas (Mar. 2023).
- We won the IMEFU National Entrepreneurship Contest (Oct. 2022).

Hyperion CCM Drone Racing Team

Mar. 2022 - Mar. 2023

Student University Racing Team at Tecnológico de Monterrey Mexico City Campus

Active Student Societies in TEC Mexico City Campus

Founder of the drone racing team representing my campus in drone competitions. **Demonstrated leadership** and innovative skills by leading a team of 30 students from various disciplines. Acquired the necessary knowledge by self-studying project management, drone components, and drone assembly.

We won the Amateur Category at Mexico Drone Nationals (Nov. 2022).

Volunteering

Peer Mentor Program at Tecnológico de Monterrey

2021 - 2024 Mexico City

Peer Mentor

CONECTA (TEC de Monterrey Newsletter)

Member of the University Program Supporting new students to adapt in their first year. One of the most successful in establishing good communication and support networks. After program completion, I am training the next generation of Peer Mentors. Still teaching self-management, study, and emotional skills.

NASCAR MEXICO SERIES

Track Marshal at Technical Inspection Team

Aug. 2022 - Jul. 2023 Nationwide, Mexico

Project on Solidarity & Sustainable City, Water and Life Staff

CONECTA (TEC de Monterrey Newsletter)

Summer 2022 Mexico City